

Antika Chowdhury

Software Developer

Profile

Experienced Data API Integration Developer, Complex problem-solver with creative and performance-oriented approach. Having around two Years of Experience in Dot net development as a .net developer and Data API Integration using IPAAS Platforms, Along with Various Business Application hands on and API Knowledge. Passionate to use the latest technologies to Develop complex Business Automation Process and Solve challenges using the best integration strategies.

Employment History

Software Development Engineer 1 at APPSeCONNECT Automation Pvt. Ltd, Kolkata

January 2023 - Present

- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs, and enhancements.
- Understand Business requirements, Gone through Business Apps API Structure and Integrated Various Apps as per business needs and Structure Complex Data Flow.
- Written Dynamics 365 Web Resource functions and Handled Complex API Integrations using Microsoft OData Rest API.
- Build class library for REST or Graph API calls format the Data into XML and manipulate the data based on the Business needs and use XPATH and XSLT fo Make the Business Data Flow.
- As a .Net Developer I have used c# programming language and .net framework to build application adapter for seamless data integration.

Software Engineer at InSync Tech-Fin Solutions Ltd., Kolkata

September 2021 — December 2022

- Coordinated with other engineers to evaluate and improve software and hardware interfaces.
- Develop API Integrations as Per Business Requirements, Understand Complex Business flows, and Solve Critical Integration challenges using XPATH, XSLT, and C# dot net.
- Written C# Dot net functions to handle Complex business data from multiple Applications and Convert in Simple XML format.

Details

Tarulia
Kolkata, 700102
India
9382033946
linkedin.com/in/antikachowdhury

Date / Place of birth

11-06-1998 Burdwan

Nationality

Indian

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

REST, GraphQL API, Ivend API

XPATH, XML, XSLT

Data Manipulation, Data Integration Development

C#, Dot Net Framework

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Ivend

Dynamics 365 CRM and BC

ERP and e-Commerce

SDS Associate at Amazon India Development Center Private LTD, Kolkata

August 2020 — August 2021

- I had act as a liaison between sellers and customers, facilitating communication and addressing any queries or concerns related to order status, delivery updates, or product information.
- If there are any issues or challenges related to delivery, I had took the responsibility for troubleshooting and resolving them.
- As a Seller Delivery Support Associate, I contribute by identifying bottlenecks or inefficiencies, I had also proposed and implement solutions to optimize the delivery experience for sellers and customers.

Education

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology, Future-Institute of Engineering and Management, Kolkata

August 2016 — July 2020

I had build several projects with HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery, PHP, MYSQL. | have knowledge of subjects like Software Engineering, Operating Systems. And Scored 7.72 CGPA in my academics

★ Accomplishments

Created Slack APP for sending notifications and Update Data of Multiple Applications from Slack channel Itself, using Slack Model and Webhook.

Developed Complete data Integration for entire Business process Automation Between iVendRetail and Shopify

Complete CLOUD COMPUTING training under ARDENT Institute.

Successfully completed "NPTEL" DBMS Certification course.

★ Declaration

I hereby declare that all the information given above is true and correct to the best of my knowledge. All the information shared in the resume is correct, and | take full responsibility for its correctness